<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zen on Josh Padnick</title>
    <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/categories/zen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zen on Josh Padnick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://JoshPadnick.com/categories/zen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Living on $1 Day</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2015/01/living-on-1-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2015/01/living-on-1-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend, I volunteered at a clinic in Puerto Peñasco, Mexico (better known to Americans as “Rocky Point”).  The clinic was makeshift, conducted in a church in a local neighborhood.  It was completely free to the residents and funded with donations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surrounding residents would be considered low income by American standards, but I sat on many pre-visit interviews with them and most of them don’t think of themselves as struggling.  They’re really just living their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The locals have differences in their lives that I simply haven’t experienced.  In my makeshift Spanish, I learned that one woman, Guadalupe, had been waiting at the free clinic for about 8 hours, not knowing when she would be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The User Interface of the Violin</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2014/08/the-user-interface-of-the-violin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2014/08/the-user-interface-of-the-violin/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, I met a friend for breakfast who’s an outstanding professional UX designer. I was curious about something:
“How do you balance the need to give people a user interface they’re familiar with and can do something with right away, against the opportunity to innovate and do new things that may take more time to learn?”
He gave a beautiful analogy in response.
     “Consider the violin. It has one of the most difficult user interfaces in the world to use. But if you’re willing to put in the thousands of hours of practice, you can make such beautiful music with it. There has to be that trade off. If we demand of our users a steep learning curve, they had better be able to produce some beautiful music.”
I like that idea because I’ve met many designers who get so mesmerized by the idea of doing something new and amazing that they lose sight of the fact that “the tradeoff” has to make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give, Give, Give, Then Get</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/09/give-give-give-then-get/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/09/give-give-give-then-get/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to try an experiment lately.  At every opportunity where I see I can possibly add value to someone in some way, I try to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can mean connecting someone with someone else I know, sharing insights from experiences I’ve had that may be applicable, or even mini-projects that leverage my technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like any other behavior change, this is a habit that takes some work to build, so I’m not 100% ramped up yet, but at least the habit is building, so hopefully after a few weeks it will just be my default behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’ve had a few interesting observations about it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your New Normal and the Futility of Stress</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/06/your-new-normal-and-the-futility-of-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/06/your-new-normal-and-the-futility-of-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a very powerful business experience about 4 years ago that taught me a lesson that I didn’t fully understand until recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the sole owner of a company that received a Letter of Intent from a publicly traded company to be acquired for around $1 million, all before I was even 30 years old. Sure sounds sexy, right?  Well, the catch was that we were not profitable at that time and of course the time between receiving a Letter of Intent and actually signing all the contracts, getting a check in the bank, and considering the acquisition a done deal can be anywhere from a few weeks to over a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we waited. Doing our best to not be too unprofitable and not incur too many legal expenses, but thrilled at the prospect of an acquisition that would instantly remove all the stress. I remember every day trying to act to the outside world like things were fine, but inside I felt incredibly stressed. Each day was a new opportunity to obsess just a little bit more about when the acquisition would finally close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then finally it did. Except that it didn’t go through, it &lt;em&gt;fell&lt;/em&gt; through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Out the Noise</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/12/cutting-out-the-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/12/cutting-out-the-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep noticing a recurring theme in my hobbies and in business: cut out the noise and focus only on the essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems so simple, but the fascinating thing about life is that the things and people we encounter so rarely do cut through the noise.  Instead it seems like most endeavors of consequence are messy, complicated and hard, and it’s not always clear why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you approach almost everything with the mentality of “how do I cut out the noise?” life becomes a very magical experience where a little effort in the right place can yield big results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think can think of at least 3 areas of my own life where cutting out the noise yielded big results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Entrepreneurship Challenge</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/06/the-fundamental-entrepreneurship-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/06/the-fundamental-entrepreneurship-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thrashing&lt;/strong&gt; n. To expend a disproportionately high amount of energy relative to the quality of output you receive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger and looked at successful companies, I simply could not for the life of me understand how they ever went from NOTHING to what they were today. The modern equivalent would be like asking “How did Jamba Juice launch hundreds of stores across the country? How did that start?” It made sense to me that if you raised a massive amount of money and then immediately bought all the capital equipment and hired all the people you needed then you’d at least be capable of serving all the customers, and that the massive revenue from the customers would balance out your massive expenses…but how did it all come to be from NOTHING? It seemed like magic to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from this line of thought I embarked on what I believe is the fundamental fallacy of entrepreneurial thinking: asking the question “what does a company need to do to succeed?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zappos Offers New Hires $3,000 to Quit After 4 Weeks</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/zappos-offers-new-hires-3000-to-quit-after-4-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/zappos-offers-new-hires-3000-to-quit-after-4-weeks/</guid>
      <description>This article was posted two years ago, but it’s still a pretty cool concept. Basically, Zappos (the online shoe site that Amazon recently bought) will train new hires for 4 weeks, and then offers them $3,000 to quit. Check it out for yourself.
I feel these kinds of counterintuitive moves have a deeper wisdom in them. Conventional wisdom says “why would ever induce someone who we just spent 4 weeks training to quit?” A more zen approach says “we only want to work with people who really want to work with us, and we believe if they take ‘the offer’ we all saved ourselves the heartache of what would have been inevitable.”
The offer above isn’t perfect and does have its drawbacks, but it’s certainly a concept worth pondering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminating Distractions</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/eliminating-distractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Nov 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/eliminating-distractions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When man’s primary job was to find a way to eat each day, distractions were probably not a big deal.  Primitive man had no facebook, no twitter, no IM, no cell phone.  He just had a rumbling in his stomach and the grim realization that either he found some food or he and possibly his family wouldn’t make it past winter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Starbucks Paradox</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/the-starbucks-paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/the-starbucks-paradox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I would say in the past month I had been going to Starbucks an average of 4 times per week.  One visit of $4.25 is easy enough to swallow, but when I started running the numbers, I was surprised to learn that $4.25 x 4 days per week x 52 weeks per year = are you telling me I spend almost $900/year sipping a latte?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I long ago realized that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/POUR-YOUR-HEART-INTO-STARBUCKS/dp/B0014JVUKU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1289550079&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;value proposition of Starbucks&lt;/a&gt; is much more than just coffee.  Howard Schultz’s original vision was not to “make premium coffee and earn a profit,” but to transport the community-ness of espresso cafes he saw in Italy to the USA, where he felt our society had only grown more isolated over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract as it may be, I think the stores do ultimately deliver on that concept.  I don’t go to Starbucks solely because I like the taste of my drink.  I go with a colleague, we know the baristas, we see people we know, it’s close by, it takes about 15 minutes…and so on.  Basically, it’s just kind of a nice way to take a break!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I needed to cut down the frequency.  So here’s the strange part.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Series of Stresses or A Series of Adventures</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/09/a-series-of-stresses-or-a-series-of-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/09/a-series-of-stresses-or-a-series-of-adventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I love what I do, one of the more frustrating aspects of running a business is that YOU are always the bottleneck for everything. The reason we don’t produce sites faster is because I, personally, have to review them. The reason sales are at X but not Y is because I personally have not yet hired the right salesperson and because I personally am too busy to proactively follow up with every single lead. The reason we haven’t developed our new products faster is because I personally have to do some user interface designs but have been busy with other things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honesty</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2009/12/honesty/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2009/12/honesty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whew, it’s been a long time since I’ve written on this blog.  Nearly 4 months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I have so many things I’d like to write about, but one thing in particular seems to keep popping up these days: the idea of being honest with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s my nature, maybe it’s my upbringing, but I just really feel uncomfortable when I’m not being forthright with someone.  If I feel like I’m withholding something or not disclosing something it makes me feel manipulative and uneasy.  I feel like I have to just come out with the truth, all of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting with Your True Purpose</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2009/08/connecting-with-your-true-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2009/08/connecting-with-your-true-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so watch this video for just a little bit before you continue reading:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;youtube&#34; style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/Pb1XXs7e7ac&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really love about music is that when we hear great music performed, we aren’t just hearing great music, we’re also hearing an individual who has risen to his or her full potential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guy in the video is of course Bono, U2’s lead singer. The song is “I Still Haven’t Found What I’m Looking For.” As you watch Bono singing to thousands of people, you can just tell that Bono has 150% embraced his role. You don’t get the feeling that he’s thinking “Gosh, am I enjoying singing this song? Is this really what I want to be doing with myself?” You can just tell that he is totally congruent with what he’s doing, and is expressing himself to his full potential. Sure enough, thousands of people came out to hear it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes, Actually Pursuing a Goal is the Worst Way to Achieve It</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/05/sometimes-actually-pursuing-a-goal-is-the-worst-way-to-achieve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2006 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/05/sometimes-actually-pursuing-a-goal-is-the-worst-way-to-achieve-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a strange phenomenon I’ve discovered in business and in life: I call them “Counter-Goals”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s a Counter-Goal? Well, it’s a goal which is achieved best by not pursuing it in the first place. Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, an example. When I was in my first year at Wharton Undergrad, I took a class called Management 100. The concept of the course was (and probably still is) quite novel. I was a member of a group of 12 other freshmen, and as a group we were tasked with completing some kind of major project. One group had to build a playground. Another group had to hold a major fundraising event. Our goal happened to be teaching the basics of economics to sixth graders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>