<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurship on Josh Padnick</title>
    <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/categories/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurship on Josh Padnick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://JoshPadnick.com/categories/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Gruntwork</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2016/05/introducing-gruntwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2016/05/introducing-gruntwork/</guid>
      <description>In November 2014, I started helping software teams ramp up on Amazon Web Services and DevOps. This was gratifying work because a few years prior, I was involved in a project that did a terrible job of DevOps and suffered greatly for it. Now I was helping other teams avoid that same fate.
And what an adventure it turned out to be! I got the chance to work with Intel, Infusionsoft, 3-person startups, a well-funded Spotify competitor and so many other interesting companies doing interesting things. I called the consulting practice Phoenix DevOps because, well, I live in Phoenix, Arizona, and it turns out the concept of immutability (sometimes known as “Phoenix Servers”) is a central tenet of DevOps.
Along the way, I wrote A Comprehensive Guide to Building Scalable Web Apps on AWS, Part 1, and gave lots of DevOps presentations at various meetups and conferences.
During that time I also discovered the outstanding Blog of Yevgeniy Brikman (“Jim”). Jim mentioned one day he was looking for DevOps people and I loved his work, so I messaged him: “Hey, I do DevOps for lots of teams and have no time right now but let’s talk!”
It turned out Jim was doing consulting very similar to what I was doing through his own consulting practice, Atomic Squirrel. And after many conversations and trial projects, we decided we really liked working with each other.
As we compared all our experiences, we realized we’d basically been doing the same thing for every client. Setup a best-practices VPC, automate deployment, setup monitoring/metrics, get ramped up on AWS, etc.
Doing consulting on an hourly basis was one paradigm for helping clients solve these problems, but what if we could solve the problems really well one time and then consult with clients merely to help them adopt what was already built? That would mean we could significantly lower the cost and time needed to get your DevOps on.
Well, that’s what we’ve decided to do! And so today, it is my pleasure to announce that I am officially winding down Phoenix DevOps and joining with Yevgeniy Brikman in a new company we call Gruntwork.
Why call it Gruntwork? Because that’s what this work is for almost every software team. Whatever app you want to build, the infrastructure stands between your vision and your app; almost no one gets excited about automating their infrastructure. Not to mention that it’s hard to find DevOps engineers, they’re often expensive, and they hold all the keys to your kingdom. And when they leave, then what?
So Gruntwork is here to do your grunt work for you, and because of the way we’ve set things up, and the thousands of hours of collective experience we have, we can help you achieve a result that’s more effective and less expensive than the most amazing DevOps person you could hire.
One other aspect of Gruntwork that’s important to Jim and me is that Gruntwork has to be able to completely disappear and you should still be ok to run your infrastructure. Would I base my important project’s entire infrastructure on a new company that was just started by a couple of guys? Only if I had complete control of the source code and could run it without them.
So, unlike most businesses which strive to build lock-in to your product, we are actively striving to build “not lock-in”. It’s actually kind of hard to do sometimes, but it means that customers can choose to come back to us not because the cost of switching is so painful but because we continue to actively provide them value.
There’s more to share in the Gruntwork story, but I think that’s enough for now and we’ll announce more when we’re ready. In the meantime, I am thrilled to be working with Jim, who’s been a fantastic business partner so far, and I am thrilled to embark on this new adventure!
Thanks for reading. Now time to get some Gruntwork done…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Common Pattern in Successful Companies</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2015/06/a-common-pattern-in-successful-companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2015/06/a-common-pattern-in-successful-companies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been helping software teams accelerate and succeed with DevOps and Amazon Web Services for a few months now (See &lt;a href=&#34;http://phoenixdevops.com/&#34;&gt;Phoenix DevOps&lt;/a&gt;), and one of the more rewarding parts of the job is getting to observe how multiple different companies operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen high-performing teams in companies that are about to IPO, software teams in Fortune 100 companies, startups of about 10 engineers, and software-based companies of no engineers at all! It’s been incredibly enlightening for me to learn about how people organize themselves to get sh*t done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Business in The Right Order</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2014/10/doing-business-in-the-right-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2014/10/doing-business-in-the-right-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I celebrated my 10th year at &lt;a href=&#34;http://omedix.com/&#34;&gt;Omedix&lt;/a&gt;, the company I started when I was 24 years old.  At 34, it is a little hard to imagine I’ve done anything for 10 years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The milestone has made me reflect on some of the early decisions I made when I first got started.  There were many really good decisions, but there were plenty of bad ones, too.  And of course when you’re in your early 20’s you have that perfect combination of extreme confidence and supreme ignorance.  Sometimes that can be a good thing, and sometimes it can be as bad as it sounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your New Normal and the Futility of Stress</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/06/your-new-normal-and-the-futility-of-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2013/06/your-new-normal-and-the-futility-of-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a very powerful business experience about 4 years ago that taught me a lesson that I didn’t fully understand until recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the sole owner of a company that received a Letter of Intent from a publicly traded company to be acquired for around $1 million, all before I was even 30 years old. Sure sounds sexy, right?  Well, the catch was that we were not profitable at that time and of course the time between receiving a Letter of Intent and actually signing all the contracts, getting a check in the bank, and considering the acquisition a done deal can be anywhere from a few weeks to over a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we waited. Doing our best to not be too unprofitable and not incur too many legal expenses, but thrilled at the prospect of an acquisition that would instantly remove all the stress. I remember every day trying to act to the outside world like things were fine, but inside I felt incredibly stressed. Each day was a new opportunity to obsess just a little bit more about when the acquisition would finally close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then finally it did. Except that it didn’t go through, it &lt;em&gt;fell&lt;/em&gt; through.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cutting Out the Noise</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/12/cutting-out-the-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/12/cutting-out-the-noise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I keep noticing a recurring theme in my hobbies and in business: cut out the noise and focus only on the essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems so simple, but the fascinating thing about life is that the things and people we encounter so rarely do cut through the noise.  Instead it seems like most endeavors of consequence are messy, complicated and hard, and it’s not always clear why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you approach almost everything with the mentality of “how do I cut out the noise?” life becomes a very magical experience where a little effort in the right place can yield big results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think can think of at least 3 areas of my own life where cutting out the noise yielded big results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Frames</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/10/the-power-of-frames/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/10/the-power-of-frames/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pitch-Anything-Innovative-Presenting-Persuading/dp/0071752854&#34;&gt;Pitch Anything&lt;/a&gt; by Mr. Oren Klaff and one of the coolest concepts in the book was the idea of “frames.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A frame is basically the set of beliefs, contexts, and assumptions that implicitly sit behind everything you communicate.  The author argues that when two people meet, their frames eventually “clash” and that only one frame can win out.  This concept was also discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pitch-Anything-Innovative-Presenting-Persuading/dp/0071752854&#34;&gt;The Game&lt;/a&gt; by Neil Strauss, but it was presented there in the context of attracting girls, not clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after I finished reading Pitch Anything, I have been blessed with a special insight into how I and others think, and to the social dynamics underlying most business transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take sales, for example.  When I first started out doing sales, my mentality was always about understanding what the client was saying as precisely as possible and, to the greatest extent possible, providing him with exactly what he requested.  But it turns out that’s not the best way to do business.  Often times, I’ve found, people respect when you challenge them because they see it as an opportunity for growth.  I realized one day that with myself, when someone challenges me head-on, I find them really interesting and then start engaging about why they disagree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fundamental Entrepreneurship Challenge</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/06/the-fundamental-entrepreneurship-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/06/the-fundamental-entrepreneurship-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thrashing&lt;/strong&gt; n. To expend a disproportionately high amount of energy relative to the quality of output you receive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was younger and looked at successful companies, I simply could not for the life of me understand how they ever went from NOTHING to what they were today. The modern equivalent would be like asking “How did Jamba Juice launch hundreds of stores across the country? How did that start?” It made sense to me that if you raised a massive amount of money and then immediately bought all the capital equipment and hired all the people you needed then you’d at least be capable of serving all the customers, and that the massive revenue from the customers would balance out your massive expenses…but how did it all come to be from NOTHING? It seemed like magic to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from this line of thought I embarked on what I believe is the fundamental fallacy of entrepreneurial thinking: asking the question “what does a company need to do to succeed?”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Technical Founder Strengths and Weaknesses</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/04/the-technical-founder-strengths-and-weaknesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/04/the-technical-founder-strengths-and-weaknesses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are hugely in favor of the technical founder. We will generally focus on companies started by strong technologists who know exactly what they want to build and how they are going to build it.”
– &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marc_Andreessen&#34;&gt;Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve always prided myself on being a “technical founder.” Basically, it means that if I were hired as a dedicated software engineer I could make a pretty meaningful contribution to a software product, but that my primary role is to guide the growth of the company as CEO. I used to think that being a technical founder was an absolute advantage over non-technical founders since not only could I do the business thing, but I could really understand at a deep technical level how viable something is, and I also know what’s possible, which enables me to come up with product ideas and visions that non-technical founders might not be able to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But life has this funny thing where our biggest strength can also be our biggest weakness. The trick is being honest with yourself about what they are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lead Like the Great Conductors</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/01/lead-like-the-great-conductors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2011/01/lead-like-the-great-conductors/</guid>
      <description>This is a beautiful exposition (and metaphor) on the role of a leader. I’ve often wondered if it’s better to set forth clear guidelines so that everyone knows exactly what to do, or better to provide people a framework within which to “tell their own story” (to use the words of Mr. Talgam in the video below).
Ultimately, I’ve found that different people respond to different styles. But if there is a “default style,” I believe the conductor who empowers the musicians to perform the music in their own style while providing subtle yet meaningful guidance on context, feeling, and intent produces the most beautiful music.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zappos Offers New Hires $3,000 to Quit After 4 Weeks</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/zappos-offers-new-hires-3000-to-quit-after-4-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2010 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/11/zappos-offers-new-hires-3000-to-quit-after-4-weeks/</guid>
      <description>This article was posted two years ago, but it’s still a pretty cool concept. Basically, Zappos (the online shoe site that Amazon recently bought) will train new hires for 4 weeks, and then offers them $3,000 to quit. Check it out for yourself.
I feel these kinds of counterintuitive moves have a deeper wisdom in them. Conventional wisdom says “why would ever induce someone who we just spent 4 weeks training to quit?” A more zen approach says “we only want to work with people who really want to work with us, and we believe if they take ‘the offer’ we all saved ourselves the heartache of what would have been inevitable.”
The offer above isn’t perfect and does have its drawbacks, but it’s certainly a concept worth pondering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Series of Stresses or A Series of Adventures</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/09/a-series-of-stresses-or-a-series-of-adventures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2010/09/a-series-of-stresses-or-a-series-of-adventures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although I love what I do, one of the more frustrating aspects of running a business is that YOU are always the bottleneck for everything. The reason we don’t produce sites faster is because I, personally, have to review them. The reason sales are at X but not Y is because I personally have not yet hired the right salesperson and because I personally am too busy to proactively follow up with every single lead. The reason we haven’t developed our new products faster is because I personally have to do some user interface designs but have been busy with other things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Great Businesspeople Also “Clever”?</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2008/08/are-great-businesspeople-also-clever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2008/08/are-great-businesspeople-also-clever/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I thought being a mega-successful entrepreneur like Richard Branson or Michael Dell was a matter of cleverness.  If you were just clever enough to figure out the right market opportunity, then you could make millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How wrong I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take Richard Branson.  For his very first entrepreneurial undertaking — when he was still just a teenager — he purchased young Chrismas Trees, planted them during the spring, and then resold them at a profit during Christmas time in the winter.  I actually do think that’s pretty clever, especially for a kid.  But really that’s as far as “clever” alone will take you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are You Ambitious or Grandiose?</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2008/06/are-you-ambitious-or-grandiose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2008/06/are-you-ambitious-or-grandiose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I really love about my life is I’ve met more entrepreneurs than I can count. One of the coolest things about entrepreneurs is that they seem to have zero demographics in common. In other words, I’ve met entrepreneurs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From both wealthy homes and poor homes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of pretty much all ethnic backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From pretty much all educational backgrounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of pretty much all ages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In equal proportion from both sexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Of course, as with any group, there are things in common. I guess “traits of an entrepreneur” is destined for another posting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is about a very important difference I’ve seen in all entrepreneurs, and here’s what it comes down to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do Entrepreneurs Become Entrepreneurs?</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/11/why-do-entrepreneurs-become-entrepreneurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/11/why-do-entrepreneurs-become-entrepreneurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rockstartup.com/&#34;&gt;RockStartup.com&lt;/a&gt;. It’s basically a documentary, split up into several episodes, that covers the birth of the website &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.payperpost.com/&#34;&gt;PayPerPost.com&lt;/a&gt; by following around the CEO/Founder, Ted, and the PR person, Britt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PayPerPost (”PPP”) is a weird concept — PPP pays bloggers to write content and sources content from Publishers, and then earns money by charging advertisers to put ads on PPP-sponsored blog sites. It’s been controversial because blogging’s rise to fame is due to its unbiased nature, and paying someone to blog, well, I guess it’s hard for them not to be biased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the success of PPP is another discussion. I’m more interested in the man behind PPP, Ted. Based on 10 minutes of watching RockStartup, I defnitely saw some “patterns” I’ve seen in other entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was at Wharton as an undergrad, in my Senior year I took an Entrepreneurship course where you had to build some unique software, come up with a business plan, and then pitch it all to VC’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our idea was terrible. We were going to build a system for people running political campaigns to help them get a sense of how people were planning on voting. We had a barcode-scanner-pen that scanned in a person’s survey responses, and then aggregated all the information so that a campaign director could see how people felt about a variety of issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Lessons in Learning How to Sell Well</title>
      <link>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/04/strange-lessons-in-learning-how-to-sell-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2006 15:56:33 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JoshPadnick.com/2006/04/strange-lessons-in-learning-how-to-sell-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never really thought of myself as a salesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember when I was younger I interned for GE and they had some career fair at the end of the summer where you met people in all the different ‘early talent identification’ programs. When I got to the sales people, they all just seemed so smooth. I didn’t trust them, and I certainly didn’t want to buy anything from them. I just couldn’t picture myself joining that table over some of the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, fast forward a few years after I started &lt;a href=&#34;http://omedix.com&#34;&gt;Omedix&lt;/a&gt; and reality struck – I had inadvertently positioned myself as the sole salesperson for our company. Either I sold our product or we didn’t do business; it was that simple. And so I had to start learning how to sell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>